# Zhijian Wen

# Curriculum Vitae

# Personal Summary

I am a graduate with Master major in Statistics, with experiences in data analysis/modelling, programming including developing R-package and data mining. I am interesting in programming and I am enjoying to "talk" with computer. I am keen to join your company where I want to utilize my skills in creative.

## Education

2016—Present Msc - Statistics, University of Auckland.

Key course: Multivariate Analysis, Data Science Practice, Statistical Inference

2015–2016 BSc(Hons) - Statistics, University of Auckland.

Key course: Bayesian Inference, Statistical Computing, Statistical Modelling class representation of **Stats 779** 

2012–2015 **BSc - Mathematics and Statistics**, *University of Auckland*.

# Projects

## Master Emulate the persp plot and filled.contour plot in gridGraphics.

The persp() is use for drawing 3-D surface and the filled.contour() is use for drawing filled level contour plot in the **graphics** package, which is the based package in **R**. My job is to convert(redraw) these two kinds of plot(functions) to **grid**. Supervisor: Associate Professor Paul Murrell

### Honours Bayesian inference on forensic glass evidence.

The aim of this project is to fit a zero inflated poisson mixture model and zero inflated negative mixture model to different situations (e.g. The breaker's distance from the window, Proportion of high persistence fragments).

Supervisor: Professor James Curran

# Work Experience

## 2016-2017 **Teaching assistant**.

**Tutor and Marker of Stats 220**: This course introduces a variety of computer technologies relevant to storing, managing, and processing data. My job is to help students to understand and solve the questions about the coding. Such as  $\mathtt{HTML/CSS}$ ,  $\mathtt{SQL}$  and  $\mathtt{R}$ 

2015-2016 **Summer Scholarship**, Working on the iNZightMaps package, used in the mapping module for iNZight.

## Skills

Advance: R, HTML, LATEX

Fair: SAS, SQL,jags, Linux, Lua, JavaScript Basic: C, C++, JAON, XML, MATLAB, Excel

# Languages

English, Mandarin, Cantonese

#### Interest

Game Computing

Statistical Computing

Table tennis

Physics

I am writing this letter to express my desire to work and innovate for you, for the world.

I enjoying on programming. Since my first year at University, I starting learning some programming language such as html/css, Matlab. During the Bachelor Degree of my university life, I learned html, xml, latex, matlab and R. R is one of my favorite programming language therefore I starting doing my Honours and Master degree to learn deeper about R.

During the summer of 2016, I was doing the summer scholarship which working on the inZightMaps package which used for the mapping module for inZight. I leaned a lot of graphics on R, specially the high-level graphics - the grid package.

Although I am a statistic student, I coding a lots and I used R to help me to analysis data to defeat any assignments and projects. I started my master dissertation with my supervisor, Dr.Paul Merrel who is a member of R core team, and now I still working on my dissertation.

Talking with computer is interesting. Although I'm not a front-line of programmer, I would like to use my coding experience to solve messy problem, and also willing to learn any other computing language in the future.

.

### Zhijian Wen

Attached: curriculum vitæ